Charles Millstein Dental History Collection MS158
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Charles Millstein Dental History Collection
1990 -- 2000
1971 -- 2015
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Millstein, Charles
MS158
1.2 Linear Feet 1 box
34 Digital Object(s)
Arrangement
This collection is arranged in received order.
Scope and Contents
This collection consists of oral history interviews, publications, and other materials relating to the history and faculty of the Tufts University School of Dental Medicine. The bulk of the material is dated from 1990 to 2000. Significant interviewees include former Tufts President John DiBaggio.
Biographical / Historical
"Dr. Charles Millstein is an Assistant Clinical Professor of Endodontics at the Tufts Dental School. He attended Brandeis University, received a D.M.D. from Tufts University School of Dental Medicine in 1962, a Certificate in Endodontics from the University of Pennsylvania in 1967 and a M.P.H. from Harvard University in 1980. He is educationally qualified for the American Board of Endodontics."
Dr. Millstein is also a dental historian and has compiled information on multiple members of the Dental School faculty, including oral history interviews.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research. This collection may require review before it is available for use. Please contact DCA for further details.
University history; Tufts University -- History; Dentistry; Dental history; School of Dental Medicine
- Minimally processed accessions, 1971 -- 2015; MS158.000034; 1.2 Linear Feet 1 box; 34 Digital Object(s)
  Conditions Governing Access
  This series may require review before it is available for use. Please contact DCA for further details.
  - Martin H. Deranian, D.D.S. interview, 2013-08-07; MS158-034
    Open for research.
    Scope and Contents
    Interview by Charles Millstein, D.M.D. Run time:1:00:39.
  - Max J. Perlitsch, D.M.D. interview, 2015-06; MS158-035
    Interview by Charles Millstein, D.M.D. Run time: 1:12:00.
  - Carole Palmer, MEd interview, 2015; MS158-036
    Interview by Dr. Charles Millstein
  - Publications and oral history interviews, 1971 -- 2009; MS158.001.GB (Box data_value_missing_22efc784f39631cf9f2b3ccfdd3116df, Box 1)
    electronic media includes cds and dvds of oral history interviews
  - Ralph W. Galen, D.D.S. Orthodontist, MS158.002.GB
  - Maury Massler, Dental Educator, 1989-08-01; MS158.003.GB
  - Dr. Louis J. P. Calisti, Dean, Tufts University School of Dental Medicine, 1963-1971, 1996-08-29; MS158.004.GB
  - Dr. Louis J. P. Calisti, Dean, Tufts University School of Dental Medicine, 1963-1971 - DVD, 1996-08-29; MS158.005.GB
    electronic media CheckSum: 92b8a75bea5c5d9c00609d89fa62dab5 Accessioned By: Veronica Martzahl, Records Archivist Accession Date: 2009-07-20 Accession Procedure: ACC-002 Stabilization By: Veronica Martzahl, Records Archivist Stabilization Date: 2009-07-24 Stabilization Procedure: ACC-007 Dates: 1996-08-29 Description: Oral history interview with Dr. Louis J. P. Calisti Checksum Application: Advanced CheckSum Verifier Media Image Application: WinImage Virus Check Application: OfficeScan Stabilization Notes: Created ISO image of video DVD. Physical disk in box 39090015513399g.
  - Harold Gelb, D.M.D. Adjunct Clinical Professor and Founder Craniomandibular Pain Center Tufts University School of Dental Medicine - CD, 1997-04-17; MS158.006.GB
  - Harold Gelb, D.M.D. Adjunct Clinical Professor and Founder Craniomandibular Pain Center Tufts University School of Dental Medicine - DVD, 1997-04-17; MS158.007.GB
  - Dedication Ceremony of the Dr. Cyril Gaum Endodontic Clinic - CD, 1991-09-20; MS158.008.GB
  - Dedication Ceremony of the Dr. Cyril Gaum Endodontic Clinic - DVD, 1991-09-20; MS158.009.GB
  - Dr. Everett Shapiro, Chairman Department of Orthodontics Tufts University School of Dental Medicine - CD, 1994-03-10; MS158.010.GB
  - Dr. Everett Shapiro, Chairman Department of Orthodontics Tufts University School of Dental Medicine - DVD, 1994-03-10; MS158.011.GB
  - Dr. J. Murray Gavel Center for Restorative Dental Research Dedication Ceremony - CD, 1992-04-10; MS158.012.GB
  - Dr. J. Murray Gavel Center for Restorative Dental Research Dedication Ceremony - DVD, 1992-04-10; MS158.013.GB
  - Muary Massler Dental Educator DVD, 1989-08-01; MS158.014.GB
  - Samuel H. Proger M.D., Chairman of the Department of Medicine, Tufts University School of Medicine - MP3, 1984; MS158.015.GB
  - Dr. Erling Johansen, Dean, Tufts University School of Dental Medicine - MP3, 1990-06-25; MS158.016.GB
  - Dr. Erling Johansen, Dean, Tufts University School of Dental Medicine - DVD, 1990-06-25; MS158.017.GB
  - Basil Bibby, International College of Dentists, Chronicles of Outstanding Leaders in Dentistry - MP3, 1998; MS158.018.GB
  - Basil Bibby, International College of Dentists, Chronicles of Outstanding Leaders in Dentistry - DVD, 1998; MS158.019.GB
  - Dedication of the Dr. Edward Becker Alumni Center - MP3, 1989-04-01; MS158.020.GB
  - Dedication of the Dr. Edward Becker Alumni Center - DVD, 1989-04-01; MS158.021.GB
  - Dr. Harold Berk, Department of Pediatric Dentistry, Tufts University School of Dental Medicine - MP3, 1994-12-07; MS158.022.GB
  - Dr. Harold Berk, Department of Pediatric Dentistry, Tufts University School of Dental Medicine - DVD, 1994-12-07; MS158.023.GB
  - Myron Allukian, DDS, MPH Director, Community Dental Programs, Boston Department of Public Health (Undergrad) - MP3, 1997-11-02; MS158.024.GB
  - Myron Allukian, DDS, MPH Director, Community Dental Programs, Boston Department of Public Health (Undergrad) - DVD, 1997-11-02; MS158.025.GB
  - Charles A. McCallum, Distinguished Professor, University of Alabama, Birmingham - MP3, 2001-04-27; MS158.026.GB
  - Charles A. McCallum, Distinguished Professor, University of Alabama, Birmingham - DVD, 2001-04-27; MS158.027.GB
  - John DiBiaggio, President Emeritus, Tufts University - MP3, 2009-01-14; MS158.028.GB
  - John DiBiaggio, President Emeritus, Tufts University - DVD, 2009-01-14; MS158.029.GB
  - John R. Saunders D.M.D. - dvd, 2011-01-07; MS158.030.GB
  - 125th Anniversary MDS/Dr. Deranian - DVD, 1989; MS158.033.GB